夢是來自內心深處的信息
每當日落 我的星球厄拉科斯都異常美麗
My planet Arrakis is so beautiful when the sun is low.
伴隨著滾滾黃沙
Rolling over the sands...
你能在空氣中感受到香料的存在
you can see spice in the air.
夜幕降臨 香料開采機在此著陸
At nightfall, the spice harvesters land.
為了躲避白天的高溫
The outsiders race against time
異星人爭分奪秒地工作
to avoid the heat of the day.
他們就在我們面前蹂躪我們的土地
They ravage our lands in front of our eyes.
他們對我們所做的一切是如此殘忍
Their cruelty to my people is all I've known.
這些異星人 哈克南人
These outsiders, the Harkonnens,
在我出生前就已經來到了這兒
came long before I was born.
他們控制了香料的生產
By controlling spice production,
從而變得極為富有
they became obscenely rich.
甚至超過了皇帝本人
Richer than the Emperor himself.
我們的戰士無法從哈克南人手中
Our warriors couldn't free Arrakis from
解放厄拉科斯
the Harkonnens,
但有一天 接到皇帝的諭旨
but one day, by Imperial decree,
他們離開了
they were gone.
皇帝為什么會這么做
Why did the Emperor choose this path?
下一個壓迫我們的人又會是誰
And who will our next oppressors be?
沙丘
（10191年）
（卡拉丹 厄崔迪家族母星）
幸好你起得早
It's good you're up early.
你父親想讓你在傳令官抵達前穿好正裝
Your father wants you in full dress before the Emperor's Herald arrives.
正裝
Full dress?
軍服嗎
Military?
穿禮服
Ceremonial.
既然都定好了 為何還要走這種形式
Why do we have to go through all this when it's already been decided?
儀式感
Ceremony.
好吧
謝謝
Thank you.
想喝水的話 可以命令我給你
If you want it, make me give it to you.
用音控力
Use the Voice.
媽媽 我剛睡醒
Mom, I just woke up.
把水遞給我
Give me the water.
杯子聽不懂你說話 命令我
The glass can't hear you. Command me.
把水給我
Give me the water.
差口氣
Almost.
差口氣嗎
Almost?
貝尼杰瑟里特姐妹會的本事 沒那么好學 保羅
Bene Gesserit skills take years to learn, Paul.
你好像很累
You look tired.
又做夢了
More dreams?
沒有
No.
極端的高溫和惡劣的氣候條件
Extreme temperatures and treacherous weather events
讓厄拉科斯城外的生存條件變得無比艱難
make life outside the cities of Arrakis truly hostile,
颶沙暴的威力甚至足以切斷金屬
with sandstorms powerful enough to cut through metal.
只有那里土生土長的弗雷曼人
Only the native tribes known as the Fremen
才能在這樣的環境中生存下來
have adapted well enough to survive.
弗雷曼人喜歡居住在
Preferring to inhabit
厄拉科斯最偏遠的地區
the remotest regions of Arrakis,
他們和巨型沙蟲共同生存在沙漠的深處
the Fremen share the deep desert with the giant sandworms
他們視沙蟲為沙漠之主
known to the Fremen as  Shai-Hulud.
由于長期接觸香料
Long exposure to spice has given
使得弗雷曼人擁有了獨特的藍色眼睛
the tribe their characteristic blue eyes,
人們稱之為湛藍之眼
the Eyes of Ibad.
外人對弗雷曼人所知甚少
Little else is known of the Fremen,
只知道他們極度危險且不可信賴
except that they are dangerous
弗雷曼人的襲擊
and unreliable.
讓香料開采行動變得異常兇險
Fremen attacks make spice harvesting extremely hazardous.
對弗雷曼人而言 香料是神圣的物質
For the Fremen, spice is the sacred hallucinogen
它能維持生命且對身體非常有益
which preserves life and brings enormous health benefits.
在帝國中
For the Imperium,
宇航公會的領航員會借助香料
spice is used by the navigators of the Spacing Guild
找到星球間安全通行的航線
to find safe paths between the stars.
沒有香料 星際航行將變得寸步難行
Without spice, interstellar travel is impossible,
這也使得香料成為了宇宙中最寶貴的物質
making it by far the most valuable substance in the universe.
微笑 哥尼
Smile, Gurney.
我在笑
I am smiling.
這次他們要花多少錢
How much will it cost them,
遠道而來走這個過場
traveling all this way for this formality?
三名公會領航員
Three Guild Navigators.
來回一共一百四十六萬零六十二帝國幣
A total of 1.46 million, 62 solaris, round trip.
承蒙柯瑞諾家族沙達姆四世皇恩
By the grace of Shaddam IV of House Corrino,
一切已知宇宙的統治者
ascendant to the Golden Lion Throne
帕迪沙皇帝的金獅王座在上
of Padishah Emperor of the Known Universe,
本人是皇帝欽點的星變傳令官
I stand before you as Herald of the Change.
儀式見證人包括帝國法庭的成員
We are witnessed by members of the Imperial Court,
宇航公會的代表
representatives of the Spacing Guild
以及貝尼杰瑟里特姐妹會的姐妹
and a sister of the Bene Gesserit.
皇帝頒布諭旨
The Emperor has spoken.
厄崔迪家族即刻獲得
"House Atreides shall immediately
厄拉科斯星球的管轄權
take control of Arrakis
全權管理那里的一切
and serve as its steward."
是否接受
Do you accept?
我們是厄崔迪家族
We are House Atreides.
我們服從皇帝的命令
There is no call we do not answer,
無條件地忠于皇帝
there is no faith that we betray.
皇帝希望我們為厄拉科斯帶去和平
The Emperor asks us to bring peace to Arrakis.
厄崔迪家族領命
House Atreides accepts.
厄崔迪 厄崔迪 厄崔迪
Atreides! Atreides! Atreides!
您的印章
Your seal.
這樣就結束了
So, it's done?
結束了
It's done.
情況怎么樣
How was it?
穩定器太松了
Stabilizers are too loose.
我們會修好的
-We'll dial it in.
謝了 伙計
-Thank you, my friend.
沒事
Got it.
鄧肯
Duncan.
好小子
My boy.
嘿
Hey. Hey.
你好 孩子
Paul, my boy.
你明天要去厄拉科斯了是嗎
So, you're going to Arrakis tomorrow.
和先遣隊一起
With the advance team.
對 明天去厄拉科斯 和先遣隊一起
Yes, I'm going to Arrakis tomorrow with the advance team.
我想你帶上我
I'd like you to take me with you.
是嗎
You would?
那太糟了 因為不行
Well, that's too bad. 'Cause no.
鄧肯
Duncan.
你想害我上軍事法庭嗎
Are you trying to get me court-martialed?
到底怎么了
What's going on?
有些話我能對你說嗎
Can I trust you with something?
當然 你知道的
Always. You know that.
我最近常做夢
I've been having dreams.
夢到厄拉科斯和弗雷曼人
About Arrakis and the Fremen.
是嗎 所以呢
Okay. So?
還夢到了你
I saw you.
和弗雷曼人一起
With the Fremen.
這是個好兆頭 意味著我能找到他們 對吧
So, I do find them. There you go. That's a good omen right there, right?
蘭威爾
Lanville!
我夢到你死了 在戰斗中死去
I saw you lying dead. Fallen in battle.
感覺要是我在場的話 你就不會死
It felt like if I had been there, you'd be alive.
首先 我不會死
First off, I'm not gonna die.
我沒跟你開玩笑
You're not taking me seriously.
所以你才想跟我一起去 聽著
That's why you want to come with me. Listen.
夢能創造故事 可醒來后發生的才最重要
Dreams make good stories, but everything important happens when we're awake.
因為那才是你要去創造的現實
'Cause that's when we make things happen.
看看你 長肌肉了
Look at you. Put on some muscle?
真的嗎
I did?
假的
No.
嘿
Hey.
我們厄拉科斯見 小子
See you on Arrakis, my boy.
父親 明天我想和鄧肯艾達荷一起
Father, I'd like to ask to join Duncan Idaho
去厄拉科斯進行偵查行動
on his scout mission to Arrakis tomorrow.
我學過弗雷曼語 能幫上忙
I've studied the Fremen language, I'd be an asset.
絕不可能
Out of the question.
你和我們其他人一樣 過幾周再過去
You'll travel in a few weeks to Arrakis, like the rest of us.
我一直都在接受訓練
I've been training my whole life.
如果不讓我面對真正的危險
What is the point if I'm not allowed
那有什么意義 你明知故問 保羅
to face some actual risk? You know why, Paul.
你是厄崔迪家族的未來
You're the future of House Atreides.
爺爺當年把斗牛當作游戲
And Grandfather fought bulls for sport!
沒錯
Yes.
可結果呢
And look where that got him.
我需要你在我身邊
I need you by my side.
我們到了那兒后會面臨巨大的危險
When we get to Arrakis, we'll face enormous danger.
什么危險
What danger?
弗雷曼人 還是沙漠
The Fremen? The desert?
政治上的危險
Political danger.
各大家族都希望我們出來領頭
The Great Houses look to us for leadership,
這威脅到了皇帝
and this threatens the Emperor.
從哈克南家族手里奪走厄拉科斯
By taking Arrakis from the Harkonnens
然后交給我們 其實是想挑起戰爭
and making it ours, he sets the stage for a war
借此削弱雙方家族
which would weaken both houses.
如果我們能借此機會
But if we hold firm,
探索出厄拉科斯真正的財富
and tap the true power of Arrakis,
我們就會變得無比強大
we could be stronger than ever.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
靠開采香料 繼續壓迫弗雷曼人
Mining spice, keeping the Fremen in their place?
這沒比哈克南人好到哪去
We'd be no better than Harkonnens.
不
No.
是靠結盟 和弗雷曼人
By making an alliance with the Fremen.
所以我才派鄧肯先過去安排
That's what I've sent Duncan Idaho to arrange.
在卡拉丹我們靠的是空氣和海洋的力量
Here on Caladan, we've ruled by air power and sea power.
在厄拉科斯 我們要學會利用沙漠的力量
On Arrakis, we need to cultivate desert power.
我要你列席委員會 了解我的計劃
I want you sitting in on my Council. Learn what I do.
如果我不是呢 爸爸
What if I'm not, Dad?
不是什么
Not what?
厄崔迪家族的未來
The future of House Atreides.
我也曾和我父親說過我不要這個
I told my father I didn't want this either.
我想當個飛行員
I wanted to be a pilot.
你從沒和我提過
You never told me that.
你爺爺曾說過
Your grandfather said,
真正的領袖不是天生的
"A great man doesn't seek to lead.
而是當使命召喚時 他會挺身而出
He's called to it, and he answers."
就算你選擇拒絕
And if your answer is no...
你依然是我心目中的那個你
you'll still be the only thing I ever needed you to be...
我的兒子
my son.
我找到了自己的路
I found my own way to it.
希望你也一樣
Maybe you'll find yours.
為了我們的先人
In their memory...
去試試吧
give it a try.
不要背對著門站
Don't stand with your back to the door.
要我和你說多少次
How many times do we have to tell you?
我能聽出你的腳步聲 哥尼哈萊克
I could tell it was you by your footsteps, Gurney Halleck.
別人可以模仿我的腳步聲
Someone might imitate my stride.
我能分得清
I know the difference.
你成新的兵器老師了
Are you the new Weapons Master?
鄧肯艾達荷不在
With Duncan Idaho gone,
我必須盡我所能
I must make do as best I can.
選兵器吧
Choose your blade.
我今天很累 哥尼
I've had quite a day, Gurney.
不如唱首歌來聽聽
Give us a song instead.
沒禮貌
That's rude.
來啊
Come on.
老家伙
Old man.
只要刀夠慢就能穿過防護盾
Ah, the slow blade penetrates the shield.
我今天沒心情
I guess I'm not in the mood today.
-心情  -對
-Mood? -Yeah.
這關心情什么事
What's mood to do with it?
戰斗是出于需要 誰在乎你的心情
You fight when the necessity arises, no matter the mood.
給我繼續
Now fight!
再來
Come on!
我贏了
I have you.
對
Aye.
但看看下面 少主
But look down, my lord.
我們會同歸于盡
You'd have joined me in death.
看來現在有心情了
I see you found the mood.
真有那么糟嗎
Will it be that bad?
你真不明白 是吧
You don't get it, do you?
你根本不明白迎接我們的將會是什么
You don't really understand the grave nature of what's happening to us.
80年來 哈克南家族統治著厄拉科斯
For 80 years, Arrakis belonged to House Harkonnen.
他們占領香料區整整80年
80 years of owning the spice fields.
那是多大一筆財富
Can you imagine the wealth?
我要在你的眼睛里看到你準備好了
Your eyes. I need to see it in your eyes.
你沒見識過哈克南人 但我有
You never met Harkonnens before, I have.
他們不是人類 而是禽獸
They're not human, they're brutal!
你必須準備好
You have to be ready.
（桀迪主星 哈克南家族母星）
男爵大人
Lord Baron.
拉班
Rabban.
最后一批飛船已經離開厄拉科斯了
The last of our ships have left Arrakis.
任務完成
It's done.
非常好
Very good.
叔叔 我們怎么可以接受
Uncle, how can we let this happen?
皇帝他怎么可以
How can the Emperor
奪走我們所建立的一切
take everything we've built
還把它給了那個公爵
and give it to that Duke?
憑什么
How?
別以為這是在厚待他
Don't be too sure it's an act of love.
他什么意思
What does he mean?
俗話說 福禍相生
When is a gift not a gift?
厄崔迪家族的呼聲越來越高
The Atreides' voice is rising,
而皇帝為人善妒
and the Emperor is a jealous man.
一個既危險又善妒的人
A dangerous, jealous man.
保羅
Paul.
保羅 醒醒
Paul, wake up.
怎么了
What's wrong?
穿好衣服 跟我來
Get dressed and come with me.
什么事
What is this?
圣母蓋烏斯海倫莫希阿姆來了
The Reverend Mother Gaius Helen Mohiam is here.
她是我在貝尼杰瑟里特姐妹會的老師
She was my teacher at the Bene Gesserit school.
現在她是皇帝的真言師
She's now Truthsayer to the Emperor himself.
她想要見見你
She would like to meet you.
為什么
Why?
她想要了解一下你的夢境
She wants to know about your dreams.
她怎么知道我的夢境
How does she know about my dreams?
為什么岳醫生也在這兒
And why is Dr. Yueh here?
他只會耽誤你一會兒
He only needs a moment.
你好 少主
Hello, young master.
你母親讓我替你檢查一下
Your mother asked me to check your vitals.
出什么事了
What's happening?
有關姐妹會的事我是略有所聞
她們說她們的存在是為了造福更多的人
我并不是要冒犯你的母親
但說到底 她們做的一切
都是為了她們自己人
你什么意思
當心點
少主一切無恙 夫人
His heart is strong as ever, my lady.
別和人提起這事
保羅
Paul...
記住你受過的訓練
你是誰
Who are you?
桀驁不馴的眼神 和他父親一樣
Defiance in the eyes. Like his father.
出去吧
Leave us.
圣母怎么說 你就怎么做
You must do everything the Reverend Mother tells you.
你在我母親家趕她出去
You dismiss my mother in her own house.
走到跟前 跪下
Come here. Kneel.
你居然敢對我用音控力
How dare you use the Voice on me?
把右手放進盒子里
Put your right hand in the box.
你母親讓你照我說的做
Your mother bade you obey me.
指著你脖子的是戈姆刺
I hold at your neck the Gom Jabbar.
一種毒針 能讓人當場斃命
A poison needle. Instant death.
測試很簡單 如果把手從盒子里抽走
The test is simple. Remove your hand from the box
你就會死
and you die.
盒子里有什么
What's in the box?
痛苦
Pain.
不必驚動侍衛
No need to call the guards.
你母親在門后守著 沒人能進得來
Your mother stands behind that door. No one would get past her.
為什么要這么做
Why are you doing this?
掉進陷阱的野獸
An animal caught in a trap
會咬斷自己的腿 以求保命
will gnaw off its own leg to escape.
你會怎么做
What will you do?
安靜
Silence.
絕不能驚慌
I must not fear.
恐懼是思維的殺手
Fear is the mind-killer.
恐懼 是最終導致滅亡的死神
Fear is the little death that brings obliteration.
我會直面恐懼 任由其穿過我的身體
And I'll face my fear and I'll permit it to pass over me and through me.
但當它過去之后
And when it has gone past...
我會洞悉它的軌跡
I will turn the inner eye and see its path.
恐懼所到之處 萬物無存
And where the fear has gone, there will be nothing.
唯我獨立
Only I will remain.
夠了
Enough.
就像用篩網濾沙子一樣 我們也會篩選人
Like sifting sand through a screen, we sift people.
如果你不能控制你內心的沖動
If you had been unable to control your impulses,
像野獸那樣
like an animal,
那我們就不能讓你活著
we could not let you live.
你繼承了太多的力量
You inherit too much power.
就因為我是公爵的兒子
What, because I'm a duke's son?
是因為你是杰西卡的兒子
Because you are Jessica's son.
你繼承的不光是身份 孩子
You have more than one birthright, boy.
杰西卡
Jessica?
你有按照姐妹會的要求訓練他
You've been training him in the Way.
和我說說你的那些夢
Tell me about these dreams.
我今晚剛做了一個
-I had one tonight.
你看到了什么
-What did you see?
一個女孩兒 在厄拉科斯
A girl. On Arrakis.
你之前夢到過她嗎
Have you dreamt of her before?
無數次
Many times.
你夢到的東西是否經常在現實中重現
Do you often dream things that happen just as you dreamed them?
并非如此
Not exactly.
再見 年輕人
Goodbye, young human.
希望你好好活下去
I hope you live.
有必要做得那么過嗎
Did you have to go that far?
你不顧姐妹會的規矩 一心訓練他
You chose to train him in the Way, in defiance of our rule.
他擁有我們的能力
He wields our power.
我必須測試出他的極限
He had to be tested to the limits.
如此天賦浪費在了一個男人身上
So much potential, wasted in a male.
告訴過你要生個女兒
You were told to bear only daughters.
可你自負地以為可以培養出一個
But you, in your pride, thought you could produce
魁薩茨哈德拉克
the  Kwisatz Haderach.
我錯了嗎
Was I wrong?
他沒死在里面 算你走運
You're lucky he didn't die in that room.
他若真是天選之人 他的路還遠著呢
If he is The One, he has a long way to go.
他的洞見力還沒有覺醒 卻又要身赴火海
His Sight is barely awakened, and now he goes into the fire.
而我們歷時百年的計劃不容有失
But our plans are measured in centuries.
如果他失敗的話 我們還有別的選擇
We have other prospects if he fails his promise.
您就這么沒信心嗎
Do you see so little hope?
關于厄拉科斯 能幫你的我們都做了
On Arrakis, we have done all we can for you.
路已經鋪好了
A path has been laid.
祈禱他不會錯失良機吧
Let's hope he doesn't squander it.
保羅
Paul.
那是什么意思
What does it mean?
說我可能是天選之人
That I could be The One?
你聽到了
You heard.
貝尼·杰瑟里特姐妹會
The Bene Gesserit serve
是幾大家族強有力的后盾
as powerful partners to the Great Houses,
但遠不止如此
but there's more to it.
你們試圖暗中操控帝國的政治走向
You steer the politics of the Imperium from the shadows.
我知道
I know.
可你不知道全部
You don't know everything.
幾千年來
For thousands of years,
我們謹慎地選擇不同的血統
we've been carefully crossings bloodlines
-就是為了培育出… -天選之人
-to bring forth... -The One?
一個先知
A mind...
他將強大到足以連接時間和空間
powerful enough to bridge space and time.
連接過去和未來
Past and future.
引領我們走向更好的未來
Who can help us into a better future.
我們相信他就快出現了
We think he's very close now.
有人認為他就在這兒
Some believe he's here.
全都是設計好的
All part of a plan.
開啟防護盾
Shield.
呼吸著時間的氣息 往事如飛沙般墜落
"My lungs taste the air of Time, Blown past falling sand..."
杜菲哈瓦特
Thufir Hawat.
我的少主
Young master!
踏上新的世界 感覺如何
How does it feel to walk on a new world?
難以克制的激動
Exciting, to say the least.
公爵大人
My lord.
怎么樣 老朋友
How are you, old friend?
先遣隊已對城市做好了防護
My advance team has secured the city.
還有幾個地區正在逐一布防
We're still smoothing out a few rough spots.
夫人
My lady.
李桑阿爾蓋布
Lisan al-Gaib!
李桑阿爾蓋布 李桑阿爾蓋布
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
別被他們的熱情騙了
Don't be fooled by the welcome.
他們只是遵照之前的規矩 強制性動作
They follow their old masters' rules. Mandatory attendance.
哈克南人喜歡這一套
That's Harkonnen love out there.
厄崔迪 厄崔迪 厄崔迪
Atreides! Atreides! Atreides!
現在送你們去能避開太陽的地方
Let's get you out of the sun.
這里的太陽能活活曬死人
The heat can kill in this place.
他們剛才指著我們
They were pointing at us.
他們在叫什么
What are they shouting?
李桑阿爾蓋布
Lisan al-Gaib.
意思是天外之音
"Voice from the Outer World."
預言中的救世主
It's their name for "messiah."
這說明姐妹會一直有在這里做事
It means the Bene Gesserit have been at work here.
灌輸迷信思想
Planting superstitions.
是為我們鋪路 保羅
Preparing the way, Paul.
幾百年來 這些人一直在等他們的救世主
These people have waited for centuries for the  Lisan al-Gaib.
他們在你身上看到了救世主的影子
They see you, they see the signs.
他們看到的都是被安排好的
They see what they've been told to see.
準備起飛
We're good to go.
屏蔽場城墻
Shield Wall.
保護城市遠離高溫和沙蟲的侵襲
Protects the city from the weather and the worms.
當地人都稱其為“上帝之手”
The locals call the big one the Hand of God.
好吧 “上帝之手”對我們的通訊系統
Well, the Hand of God is wreaking havoc
造成了嚴重的破壞
on our comms system.
太安靜了
It's so quiet.
是的
Yeah.
這也正是我擔心的
That's what worries me, too.
那兒是飛船港
There's the spaceport
揚塵的地方是香料提煉廠
and that plume of dust there is the spice refinery.
兩個最容易受襲的地方
Our two most vulnerable points.
我要你守好它們
I want you guarding them.
如果沒法把香料送去別的星球
If we can't refine spice and ship it off-world,
那就只能等死
- we're dead here.
大人
- My lord.
太陽太曬了 我們得關閉大門
The sun's getting too high. We need to seal the doors.
怎么形容這破地方來著
What do they say about this hellhole again?
想洗澡 就拿沙子擦你的屁股
"To shower, you scrub your ass with sand," my lord.
他們是這么說的
That's what they say.
確實是這樣
這些是管家的人選 夫人
Candidates for a housekeeper, my lady.
你叫什么
What is your name?
我叫夏道特梅帕絲 夫人
Shadout Mapes, my lady.
其他人下去吧 謝謝
The rest of you may go. Thank you.
夏道特
Shadout.
這是弗雷曼的古語
It's an old Chakobsa word.
汲水斗的意思
"Well-dipper."
你是弗雷曼人 你知道這兒的古語
You know the ancient tongues?
我還知道很多
I know many things.
比如你在衣服里藏著一把武器
I know that you have a weapon concealed
還不是時候
in your bodice.
如果你想要害我
If you mean to harm me,
我必須提醒你 無論你手里藏了什么
I must warn you, whatever you're hiding,
都不會管用的
it won't be enough.
這把武器將會是個禮物
The weapon is meant as a gift
如果你真是天選之人的話
if you are truly The One.
你知道這個嗎
Do you know this?
這是把晶牙匕
It's a crysknife.
知道它的寓意嗎
Do you know its meaning?
準備動手
它是沙漠之主的…
It's a maker...
沙漠深處的造物主
A maker of the deep desert.
當你相信一個預言太久
When you have lived with prophecy for so long,
預言實現的那一刻反而會讓你震驚
the moment of revelation is a shock.
李桑阿爾蓋布 那對母子
Lisan al-Gaib. The mother and the son.
它是你的了
It is yours.
它是沙漠之主的牙齒
Tooth of  Shai-Hulud.
李桑阿爾蓋布 李桑阿爾蓋布
Lisan! Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
你好
Hello.
這個點你不應該到外面來
You shouldn't be out here at this hour of the day.
他們不也在外面
They're out here.
他們是來朝拜的
Fremen pilgrims.
他們無所謂會不會中暑
They don't care about heatstroke.
真沒想到這里還能有棗椰樹
I didn't know date palms could even be found out here.
這些不是土生土長的
these aren't indigenous.
沒有我它們活不下去
They can't survive without me.
它們中的每一棵
Each one of these
都要喝掉相當于5個人的飲水量
drinks every day the equivalent of five men.
一共20棵樹 100個人
Twenty palm trees. A hundred lives.
那是不是該移走它們 省點水
Should we remove them? Save the water?
不
No, no, no.
這些是圣樹
These are sacred.
舊時的夢
Old dream.
在厄拉科斯 體型最大也最危險的生物
The largest and most dangerous organism on Arrakis is
就是沙蟲 身長可以達到400米
the sandworm, capable of reaching 400 meters in length.
為了避免發出帶有節奏的聲響
To avoid making rhythmic noises,
而引來沙蟲
which attract the sandworms,
弗雷曼人選擇用沙地微步在沙漠里行走
the Fremen cross desert spaces using the sandwalk,
這種步伐宛如跳舞 毫無節奏可言
a dance-like motion with irregular rhythm which emulates
正如沙漠本身的聲音
the natural sounds of the desert.
今天的厄拉科斯仍有植物幸存
What scant plant life exists on Arrakis
全要歸功于弗雷曼人
is thanks to the Fremen,
他們一直在種植深入土壤的地球植物
who have cultivated deep-rooted terranic plants
例如仙人掌 驢灌木 沙地馬鞭草 以及香灌木
such as saguaro, burrobush, sand-verbena and incense bush.
據記載 牧羊人樹的樹根是最長的
The shepherd's tree has the deepest documented roots,
可以伸入超過137米深的地下
stretching more than 450 feet deep.
這些植物都可以在炎熱且貧瘠的
These plants cling to life in a parched,
沙漠土地中生存
nutrient-poor landscape.
是獵殺鏢
It's a hunter-seeker.
操控者一定就在附近
The operator must be nearby.
站一邊去
有個哈克南探子
The Harkonnen agent was cemented
六周前被水泥封在了洞里
into that hole six weeks ago.
然后通過水管在墻里操控獵殺鏢
Ran the hunter-seeker through a water pipe inside the walls.
我讓您失望了 沒什么好辯解的
Sire, I failed you today. There's no excuse.
我向您請辭
You have my resignation.
你要我們的損失變得更大嗎
You would deprive us of your talents at this time?
大人 我的榮耀…
Sire, my honor demands...
這些人想要我兒子的命
They tried to take the life of my son!
我才不關心你的榮耀呢
I don't give a damn about your honor.
想將功補過的話 多抓幾個間諜回來
You want absolution? Go catch some spies.
遵命
Your Grace.
讓這東西出去
The thing must leave.
您但說無妨 我們的寵物聽不懂您的話
You can speak without fear. Our pet doesn't understand your language.
出去
Get out.
它聽得懂
It understands.
開啟隔音錐區
Activate silence.
皇帝怎么說
他會出手相助
借助他的薩多卡軍團
這事絕不能走漏風聲
It must never be known.
整個厄拉科斯星球沒有衛星
There's no satellites over Arrakis.
厄崔迪家族會無聲無息地死去
The Atreides will die in the dark.
關于這一點
On that matter,
我們姐妹會并不關心厄崔迪公爵的死活
Duke Leto Atreides means nothing to our order.
但他的妻子是我們的人 還有她的兒子
But his wife is under our protection and by extension, her son.
讓他們有尊嚴地被流放
Allow them the dignity of exile.
我們哈克南家族永遠不會違背
House Harkonnen would never dream of violating
姐妹會的圣令
the sanctity of your order.
我向你保證 我們不會傷害他們
I give you my word. We will not harm them.
如果放過公爵的兒子
If the Duke's son lives...
厄崔迪家族都得死
No Atreides will live.
大人 你剛答應過那巫婆
My lord, you gave your word to the witch.
她會知道的
She sees too much.
我說了不會傷害他們 我會做到
I said I would not harm them. And I shall not.
但那里可是厄拉科斯
But Arrakis is Arrakis.
沙漠容不下弱者
And the desert takes the weak.
我的沙漠
My desert.
我的厄拉科斯
My Arrakis.
我的沙丘
My Dune.
第一次參加戰略會議
Your first strategy meeting.
保羅·厄崔迪徒手抓住了一枚獵殺鏢
Paul Atreides, who catches hunter-seekers in his bare hands
就像古時候的英雄一般
like a hero of old.
謝謝你當眾羞辱我 老家伙
Thanks for the humiliation, old man.
我會盯著點的
Gotta keep an eye on you.
起立
Attention!
開始吧
Let's get started.
杜菲 匯報一下情況
Thufir. Operations.
我拿到了哈克南人賬本的復印件
I secured a copy of the Harkonnens' account books.
那些哈克南人
The Harkonnens were taking
每年都會從這里獲利100億帝國幣
10 billion solaris out of here every year.
他們要吸取海里的財富 沙中隱藏的珍寶
"They shall suck of the abundance of the seas, and the treasure hid in the sand."
短時間內我們達不到那么高的收益
We won't see profits like that for a while.
他們留下的設備太落后了
Not with the equipment they left us.
有多落后
How bad is it?
這些是香料中轉塔
These are spice silos.
我們得填滿這里的每一個塔箱
We're meant to fill every crate.
每一個嗎
All of them?
每25個標準日一輪
Every 25 standard days.
哈克南人拖慢了我們的進度
Harkonnen sabotage slows us down.
那誰來仲裁呢
But who's meant to arbitrate?
難道沒有裁決官來監督交接嗎
Isn't there a Judge of the Change to oversee the transition?
皇帝指派了誰
Who did the Emperor appoint?
列特凱恩斯博士 帝國的星球全知
Dr. Liet Kynes. Imperial Ecologist.
到這兒20年了 據說她為人很古怪
Been here 20 years. Eccentric, from what I'm told.
我要親自查看一下開采場
I want to see these harvesting fields myself.
我不建議您這么做
I wouldn't recommend it, my lord.
讓這位裁決官陪同我們一起 我們早該見面了
Have this Judge of the Change accompany us. A meeting's long overdue.
總得尋求點帝國的庇護吧
And we'll get a bit of Imperial protection.
找個人質 我喜歡
A hostage. I love it.
他來了 大人
He's here, my lord.
放心跟他們走
客氣點 他們是朋友
Take care of them. They are friends.
鄧肯
Duncan!
好小子
Ah! My boy!
-你好像長高了 -而你卻變臭了
I swear you're getting taller. Well, you smell much worse.
有好多事要和你說 走吧
我和弗雷曼人相處了四周
For four weeks, I lived with the Fremen.
躲在沙漠中一個叫地下城的地方
Hidden in the desert, in a community called a  sietch.
他們的領袖斯第爾格和我一同回來見您
Stilgar, the leader of that  sietch, has come with me to meet you, sire.
那個地下城 怎么隱蔽起來的
This  sietch,  how is it hidden?
它在地下 厄拉科斯到處是洞穴
It's underground. Arrakis is filled with caverns.
那地方有多大
How big was the place?
大約有一萬人 而地下城有上百個
I'd say 10,000 people. And there are hundreds of  sietches.
上百萬的弗雷曼人
Millions of Fremen.
你說對了
You were right.
哈克南人估計整個星球上
The Harkonnen estimate was 50,000 on
只有五萬個弗雷曼人
the whole planet.
他們看著我找了他們好幾天
The Fremen watched me search for them for days.
我一直沒見到他們
I never saw them.
后來他們派了名戰士來殺我
Finally, they sent a warrior out to kill me.
不得不說
And I gotta tell you,
這次我差點小命不保
I have never come so close to dying.
帝國上下無人能比
There's no finer fighter in the Imperium.
他們打起來特別兇
They fight like demons.
沙漠的力量
Desert power.
鄧肯 做得好
Duncan.-Well done.
謝謝大人
-Thank you, my lord.
閣下 那名領袖身上有刀 他不肯上交
Sire. Their leader has a knife he won't surrender, sire.
是晶牙匕 是他們的圣物
It's a crysknife. It's sacred to his people.
讓他進來
Let him pass.
停下來
Stop there.
嘿
Hey! Hey!
斯第爾格
Stilgar.
歡迎你
Welcome.
先生 凡是尊重我的人
Sir, I respect the personal dignity
我一定也會以禮相待
of any man that respects mine.
慢著
Hold.
謝謝你 斯第爾格
Thank you, Stilgar,
用你寶貴的水分作為見面禮
for the gift of your body's moisture.
我們接受你的這份誠意
We accept it in the spirit in which it was given.
很高興你能來
I'm glad you've come.
我相信我們兩方的人民
I believe your people and mine
有許多地方可以互幫互助
have much to offer one another.
不 你們這些異星人為了香料而來
No, no, you are Outworlders. You come here for the spice,
你們一味地索取 從不懂得回報
you take it, giving nothing in return.
說得對
That's true.
我知道你們一直遭受著哈克南人的壓迫
I know you've suffered at the hands of the Harkonnen.
說說你想要什么
Name what you want.
只要我能力所及 我都會無條件答應你
If it's in my power to grant, I'll give it and ask for nothing.
我希望你們不要去找我們的地下城
Mm. I ask for this. Do not seek our  sietches.
不要入侵我們的領地
Do not trespass in our lands.
早在你們來之前 這片沙漠就是我們的
The desert was ours long before you came.
你們可以來挖香料 但一旦挖到
So, come and dig your spice, but when you have it,
就請回到屏蔽場城墻里面
go back to this side of the Shield Wall
把沙漠留給弗雷曼人
and leave the desert to the Fremen.
你得稱呼公爵“大人”或者“閣下”
You will address the Duke as "my lord" or "sire."
哥尼 你先等一下
Gurney, just... Just a moment.
皇帝賜予我厄拉科斯作為封地
The Emperor has given me Arrakis as my fief
讓我統治并保護它
to rule and protect.
我無法保證自己不會踏入沙漠
I cannot promise not to travel into the desert
如果職責需要的話
if duty compels me.
但地下城永遠屬于你們
But your  sietches will be yours forever.
只要有我在 你們永遠不會被追殺
And you will never be hunted while I govern here.
我欽佩你的承諾
That's very honorable.
我得走了 我要說的就是這些
I must go. That's all I have to say to you.
不留下來嗎 我們會款待你
Won't you stay? We would honor you.
我的使命不在這里
Honor requires that I be elsewhere.
我認得你
我不喜歡他
I don't like him.
看來計劃初有成效
Our plan bears fruit.
但還需要時間
But it will take time?
沒錯 確實需要點時間
Yes. It will take time.
這個給你
Here, this is for you.
這是定位羅盤
It's a paracompass.
這里的衛星都有磁場 所以
The moons here have a magnetic field, so...
普通的羅盤不會指向北方
a simple compass needle won't point north.
需要精妙的發條來解決問題
Takes a clever piece of clockwork to sort it out.
弗雷曼人做的嗎
The Fremen make these?
還有蒸餾服 沙實機
And stillsuits, and sand compactors,
各種各樣精致的小玩意兒
and all kinds of ingenious things.
沙實機又是什么
What the hell is a sand compactor?
這就是沙實機
That's a sand compactor.
行啊 伙計 你快混成原住民了
My God, man, you've gone native.
你喜歡他們
You admire them.
確實
I do.
他們兇猛 但忠誠 天生屬于沙漠
They're fierce but loyal. They're attuned to the desert.
他們能融入沙漠 同時也包容著它
Part of it. It's part of them.
見到就知道了
You wait till you see it.
那里風景也很美
It's beautiful out there.
全體注意 日出警告
Sunrise warning, all workers.
今天的溫度將達到60攝氏度
Temperature today will reach 140 degrees.
現在溫度是32攝氏度
We are currently 90 degrees,
10分鐘后上升至49攝氏度
and in 10 minutes, we will hit 120 degrees.
最后通知 全體注意 日出警告
Last warning call.
場地將于十分鐘后關閉
對接一處 對接二處
今天早晨各個工作區域溫度正常
預計保持在75攝氏度左右
北方和東北方向刮來的風將帶來大量沙塵
這位是裁決官 閣下
The Judge of the Change, sire.
列特凱恩斯博士
Dr. Liet Kynes.
公爵大人 歡迎來到厄拉科斯
My lord Duke. Welcome to Arrakis.
你就是那個星球全知
You're the Imperial Ecologist.
謝謝你的蒸餾服
Thank you for the stillsuits.
那是弗雷曼人制作的
They are of Fremen make.
最好的
The best.
請允許我檢查您的蒸餾服是否完好
With your permission, sire, I must check the integrity of your suit...
沒關系
It's all right.
凱恩斯博士 一切交給你了
Dr. Kynes, we're in your hands.
蒸餾服是一種非常高效的過濾凈化系統
A stillsuit is a high-efficiency filtration system.
即便是大清早
Even this early in the morning,
沒有它 你們兩個小時都撐不過
you wouldn't survive two hours without one of these.
它能冷卻身體
It cools the body
吸收汗水然后循環利用
and recycles the water lost to sweat.
只要你們在動 衣服就會運作
Your body's movements provide the power.
面罩里面有根管子 你們可以用它喝過濾后的水
Inside the mask, you'll find a tube to allow you to drink the recycled water.
運作良好的話
In good working order,
它能保證你們每天只損失少量水分
your suit won't lose more than a thimbleful of water a day.
真是好東西
Most impressive.
看看你的 孩子
Let's have a look at you, lad.
你以前穿過蒸餾服
You've...worn a stillsuit before?
不 我第一次穿
No, this is my first time.
你的沙地靴腳踝那兒的松緊帶箍得正好
Your desert boots are fitted slip-fashion at the ankles.
誰教你的
Who taught you to do that?
感覺就該那樣穿
It seemed the right way.
他了解你們的習慣 仿佛與生俱來
你是弗雷曼人
Are you Fremen?
這里地下城和村莊里的人都愿意接納我
I am accepted in both  sietch  and village.
好了 和我去看看香料沙吧
Now, come and see the spice sands
你們往后的生計都得靠它
on which your livelihood depends.
萬一撲翼機掉下去了怎么辦
What would you do if your ornithopter went down out here?
掉在這里可就慘了 這里是沙蟲的地盤
You wouldn't want to go down out there. It's worm territory.
是沙塵云
Dust cloud.
看見了
I see it.
那是你們的香料開采車
That's one of your harvesters.
你們能看到地面上散布著香料
You can see the spice scattered over the surface.
這里香料濃度很高 從顏色判斷
A rich spice bed by the color.
飛得再高一點會看得更清楚
If you get a little higher, you'll have a better view.
那幾架偵察機是在找蟲跡
You see these spotter aircraft looking for wormsign.
蟲跡
Wormsign?
一條涌向開采車的沙浪
A sand wave moving toward the crawler.
沙蟲游走在深處 但發動襲擊時會靠近地表
Worms travel deep but get closer to the surface when they attack.
如果你們愿意等的話 應該能看到一條
If you are patient, we should see one.
沙蟲經常出沒嗎
A worm always comes?
經常 有節奏的聲音會吸引它們
Always. They're drawn by rhythmic noises.
給開采車加上防護盾不就行了
Why don't we just shield the crawlers?
防護盾在沙漠就是死亡信號
A shield's a death sentence in the desert.
它們會引來沙蟲 誘使沙蟲大開殺戒
It attracts the worms and drives them into a killing frenzy.
那是沙蟲嗎
Is that a worm?
還是條大的
Big one.
你眼力不錯
You have good eyes.
呼叫開采車德爾塔-埃阿斯九號
Calling crawler Delta Ajax niner.
發現蟲跡 請注意
Wormsign warning. Acknowledge.
誰在呼叫德爾塔-埃阿斯九號 完畢
Who calls Delta Ajax niner? Over.
他們好像還挺淡定
They seem pretty calm about it.
臨時飛行 處理帝國事務
Unlisted flight. Imperium business.
蟲跡在開采車的東北方向 距離3.7公里
Wormsign north and east of you. 3.7 kilometers.
德爾塔-埃阿斯九號 我是一號偵察機
Delta Ajax niner, this is Spotter One.
確認發現蟲跡
Wormsign confirmed.
稍后確認接觸時間
Stand by for contact fix.
沙蟲正沿著偵查路線向你靠近 五分鐘后接觸
Worm is on intercept course to your position. Contact in five minutes.
接下來會怎么樣
So, what happens now?
他們會叫運載器吊起開采車
They'll call a carryall to lift the crawler.
開采車會工作到最后一分鐘
They'll harvest right up to the last minute.
呼叫運載器阿爾法零號 請求進行對接
Calling carryall Alpha Zero. Ready for docking sequence.
五分鐘后接觸 完畢
Contact five minutes. Over.
有人能看到運載器嗎
Anybody got a visual on the carryall?
在那邊
There it is.
運載器阿爾法零號 對接德爾塔-埃阿斯九號
This is carryall Alpha Zero to Delta Ajax niner.
從你的東邊靠近
Approaching from your east.
調整高度 啟動對接裝置
Correcting altitude and preparing docking equipment.
收到 阿爾法零號 啟動對接程序
Copy, Alpha Zero. Initiating docking sequence.
-D5 -收到
T-5. Copy that.
30秒后準備升空
Prepare to be airborne in 30 seconds.
對接程序已經啟動 做好安全防護
Docking sequence initiated. Brace yourselves.
阿爾法零號 有一個點沒對接上
Alpha Zero, we're short one point of contact.
什么情況
What is going on?
有個固定器 它失靈了
It's one of the anchors. It's dead.
是三號對接點 該死
Shit.
運載器缺少一個固定點
Carryall unable to receive.
無法繼續進行升空操作
Unable to lift without that anchor.
緊急呼叫
All call! All call!
區域內所有運載器 收到請回答
Any carryall in the sector, please respond!
偵察機 更新數據 完畢
Spotter One, give us an update. Over.
液壓裝置壞了 無法修復 盡快撤離
Hydraulics are dead. We won't make it. You have to evacuate.
-四分鐘后接觸 -再試一次
Contact in four minutes. Try it again!
-開采車上有多少人  -一共21人
How many men on that crawler? Crew of 21.
我們每艘飛船能帶6個人 還差3個
Our ships can take six each. That's still three short.
會有辦法的
We'll find a way.
我是雷托厄崔迪公爵
This is Duke Leto Atreides.
我們來幫德爾塔-埃阿斯九號進行撤離
We're coming down to extract the crew of Delta Ajax niner.
我們會停在西邊
We'll set down on the west.
每個護盾發電機的重量是100公斤
Shield generators weigh 100 kilos each.
沒錯 哥尼
Yes, Gurney,
讓我們的護衛把護盾發電機扔出去
have our escorts throw out the shield generators.
遵命 閣下
Yes, sire.
保羅 你到飛船后面去 領他們上船
And, Paul, I want you at the back of the thopter. Guide them in.
德爾塔-埃阿斯九號
Delta Ajax niner,
七個人一組 分別上我們的飛船
put seven men each in my ships now.
兩分鐘后接觸
Contact in two minutes.
十五號線 收到請回復
越來越近了 伙計們
Getting close, guys.
還是趕緊棄車為妙
We better abandon ship now.
請調回一號頻道
他們人呢
Where are they?
大人 我們必須按規章行事
Sir, there's protocol for a reason.
擅自離開和送死沒什么差別
If we take one step out there, we're as good as dead.
而且我們車上裝滿了香料 不能棄之不理
Besides, we've got a full load of spice. -We can't just leave it.
去他的香料 所有人立刻撤離開采車
-Damn the spice! I want every man off that crawler now!
去那邊 去那邊
快點 快
嘿
Hey! Hey!
這邊7個人 那邊7個人
Seven over here, seven over there.
動作快 快
Go! Go! Go!
魁薩茨哈德拉克 李桑阿爾蓋布
Kwisatz Haderach.
魁薩茨哈德拉克覺醒吧
Kwisatz Haderach  awakes.
快點 快上去 還有一個呢 只有六個人
Hurry! Get on!
快走 快 快 快
沙蟲來了
It's here!
保羅
Paul!
我能聽出你的腳步聲 老家伙
I recognize your footsteps, old man.
保羅 起來
Get up!
我們走
Let's go!
你怎么了 振作點 我們走
What's the matter with you? Come on! Let's go!
快跑
Run!
嘿
Hey!
保佑造物主和他的水
Bless the Maker and His Water.
保佑他的降臨與逝去
Bless the coming and going of Him.
愿他的到來能凈化這個世界
May His passage cleanse the world
為他的子民守護這個世界
and keep the world for His people.
嘿
Hey!
-你不可以像剛才那么冒險 -是 長官
- You cannot take such risks. - Yes, sir.
-你身上肩負著責任 -抱歉
You have responsibilities. I... I'm sorry, sir.
-不會有下次了 -走
It won't happen again. Go.
凱恩斯博士
Dr. Kynes.
你看到了
You saw it.
你親眼所見 很明顯
With your own eyes. It's plain to see.
他們留下的都是些破銅爛鐵
Everything they've left us is in shambles.
我們被他們擺了一道
We've been set up to fail.
運載器只是老化了
That carryall was just old.
沙漠對機器一向不太友好
The desert isn't kind to equipment.
如果香料的產量恢復不了
You know what will happen
你知道會有什么后果
if I don't get spice production back on track.
我的職責并不是替你們說話
I'm not here to take your part.
鐵打的厄拉科斯 流水的統治者
Arrakis has seen men like you come and go.
照顧好你的家人
Take good care of your family.
沙漠對人類也不會太友好
The desert's not kind to humans either.
香料是一種作用于精神的化學物質
Spice is a psychoactive chemical.
你好像對它比較敏感
You seem to be sensitive.
沒什么大礙
You'll be fine.
謝謝你 岳醫生
Thank you, Dr. Yueh.
根本不是因為過敏
That wasn't an allergic reaction.
我看到了幻象
I had a vision.
我睜大眼睛看
My eyes were wide open.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
魁薩茨哈德拉克
Kwisatz Haderach.
你能看得到
You can see.
夢境很混亂
It's confusing.
我好像看到我死了 但又不是
I thought I saw my death, only it wasn't.
有一把匕首 它很重要 不知為何
I know a knife is important, somehow.
有人會給我一把匕首
Someone will hand me a blade,
可又不知會是何人 何時 何地
but I don't know who, or when, or where.
可又有一些事 我心里很清楚 我能感受到
Some things, though, are crystal clear. I can feel it.
我知道你懷孕了
I know you're pregnant.
你怎么會知道
You can't know that.
我自己也才剛知道 只有幾周而已
I barely know that. It's only been a few weeks.
（薩多卡監獄星球 帝國軍隊大本營）
（薩多卡語）
男爵為什么需要我們
哈克南家族的人數遠超過厄崔迪家族
厄崔迪軍團是整個帝國中最出色的
Atreides legions are the finest in the Imperium.
由哥尼哈萊克 鄧肯艾達荷訓練
Trained by Gurney Halleck and Duncan Idaho.
我們是薩多卡軍團
皇帝的精銳部隊
和我們作對的人絕沒好下場
沒錯
Just so.
三個營 約定好的
Three battalions. As agreed.
皇帝下令 自當奉命行事
關于保羅 我有事要告訴你
There is something you need to know about Paul.
不
No.
我并不想知道
Don't think I want to know.
自從你的圣母來過后 他就變得不一樣了
Ever since you brought him before your Reverend Mother, he hasn't been the same.
變得心神不寧
He's distracted.
杰西卡 你給了我一個兒子
Jessica, you gave me a son.
打從他出生 我從沒質疑過你
And from the moment he was born, I never questioned you.
我毫無保留地信任你
I trusted you completely.
即便你背著我行事
Even when you walked in shadows.
現在我就問你一個問題
Now I'm asking you this one thing.
如果真的有事
If anything happens...
你會保護我們的兒子嗎
will you protect our son?
不惜我的性命
With my life.
我問的不是他的母親
I'm not asking his mother.
而是貝尼杰瑟里特的一員
I'm asking the Bene Gesserit.
你會保護保羅嗎
Will you protect Paul?
你為什么會有這些想法
Why are you having these thoughts?
雷托 這不像你
Leto, this is not you.
我以為我們還有時間
I thought we'd have more time.
睡個好覺 保羅少主
Have a good night, Master Paul.
晚安 岳醫生
Good night, Dr. Yueh.
你需要好好睡一覺
You need to sleep.
不 我不想靠那個
No. Not like that.
我應該娶你的
I should have married you.
杜菲 叫侍衛
Hawat. Security.
侍衛
Security.
長官
Sir. Sir.
防護盾失靈了
The shield's come down.
動作快 拿上武器 快跟上
見鬼
God in heaven.
啟動所有武裝飛行器 快走
Get everything with guns off the ground! Go!
沖啊
Go! Go! Go!
去那兒 小心了
快走
跟我走
With me! With me!
一起上
厄崔迪 厄崔迪
Atreides! Atreides!
是薩多卡軍團
- Sardaukar! - Sardaukar!
抱歉 公爵大人
I'm sorry, my lord.
我和男爵做了個交易
But I've made a bargain with the Baron.
為什么
Why?
我別無選擇
I had no choice.
哈克南人抓了我妻子 瓦娜
The Harkonnens have my wife, Wanna.
他們把她當玩具一樣折磨
They take her apart like a doll.
我要把她救出來
I will buy her freedom.
用你做交換
And you are the price.
對于保羅 我會盡可能幫他
For Paul. I will do what I can.
而你 我要你替我殺一個人
And you will kill a man for me.
我會替你換掉你的錐形牙
I'm going to replace your peg tooth.
只要你用力一咬
If you bite down hard,
這顆牙就會碎裂
this tooth will crush.
呼口氣 空氣中就將充滿毒氣
Breathe out, and you will fill the air with poison.
那將是你的最后一口氣
It will be your last breath.
但如果你選的時機準確
But if you choose your moment well,
那也將是男爵的最后一口
it will also be the Baron's.
保羅
Paul.
一會兒把他們扔到沙漠里去
讓沙蟲吃掉他們
為什么不直接殺了他們
因為我們要面對一個真言師
我們可以說我們沒有殺他們
有疤的那個是聾子
去死吧 走狗們
To hell, dogs!
我從沒和貴族試過
I've never had a highborn.
你呢
You?
貝尼杰瑟里特姐妹會算不上貴族
Bene Gesserit ain't all highborn.
對我來說 已經算是了
She's highborn enough for me.
把那孩子拿去喂沙蟲 好好和她告別吧
Let's feed the kid to the worms. And give her a long goodbye.
你們敢動我母親一下試試
Don't you dare touch my mother.
不許說話
Don't talk.
別亂來 你還沒準備好
扯下她嘴上的布
Remove her gag.
閉嘴
Shut up.
找到正確的音調
走得夠遠了
把那個男孩兒丟下去吧
扯下她嘴上的布
Remove her gag.
殺了他
Kill him.
放了我們
Set us free.
住手
Stop!
割斷繩子
Cut the rope.
把刀給我
Give me the knife.
你的音調 太刻意了
Your pitch was too forced.
是弗雷曼生存包
It's a fremkit.
他們損毀了飛船
They've crippled the ship.
你這兒的廚子還不錯 表兄
You have a wonderful kitchen, cousin.
這是岳醫生的筆跡
This is Dr. Yueh's handwriting.
如果有人活著逃出厄拉肯
"If anyone makes it out of Arrakeen alive,
生存包里有厄崔迪的信號器
there's an Atreides beacon in the fremkit.
但愿他們能找到你
God willing, they'll be able to find you."
男爵大人 岳醫生到了
My lord Baron. Dr. Yueh.
那個叛徒
The traitor.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我干擾了他們的通訊
I jammed their comms
解除了護盾
and lowered their shields.
還帶來了公爵和他的家人
I delivered the Duke and his family.
和約定的一樣
The bargain to the letter.
那我該為你做些什么
And what was I to do for you?
放了我妻子 別再折磨她
Deliver my wife from her agony.
沒錯
Yes.
我說過會放了她
I said I'd set her free.
讓你們團聚
That you could join her.
下去陪她吧
So, join her.
你覺得接下來該怎么做
What do you think is next?
是沙槌 但沒有蒸餾服
It's a thumper. No stillsuits.
那才是我們最需要的
The one thing we actually need.
幾百年來 我們兩家的仇恨不共戴天
For hundreds of years, we've traded blood for blood.
該結束了
But no more.
你的兒子死了 你的女人也跟著死了
Your son is dead. Your concubine is dead.
今晚厄崔迪家族就此隕落
Tonight the House of Atreides falls.
你的血脈將從此斷絕
And your bloodline ends forever.
你說什么
What did you say?
我既來此 必當永世留存
Here I am...here I remain.
凱恩斯
Kynes!
你待在這里不安全
It's not safe for you here.
你會告訴蘭茲拉德聯合會 我們被出賣了嗎
Will you tell the Great Houses of the Landsraad how we were betrayed?
告訴他們我們的人是如何被殺害的
How the best of them were murdered?
我接到的命令是保持沉默
I am commanded to say nothing.
什么都沒看到
To see nothing.
皇帝是想我們來送死
The Emperor sent us here to die.
帳篷里有香料
There's spice in the tent.
這就是未來 它來了
That's the future. It's coming.
生生不息的戰火蔓延了整個宇宙
Holy war spreading across the universe like unquenchable fire.
保羅 你在害怕 我能感受到
Paul, you're scared. I can see it.
告訴我你在害怕什么
Tell me, please, what do you fear?
誰來救救我 求你了
Somebody help me, please.
保羅
Paul.
它來了
It's coming.
我看到生生不息的戰火
I see a holy war spreading across
蔓延了整個宇宙
the universe like unquenchable fire.
一名勇士以我父親的名義
A warrior religion that waves
揮舞著厄崔迪家族的戰旗
the Atreides banner in my father's name.
-保羅 -狂熱的追隨者聚集成眾
Paul. Fanatical legions worshipping
祭拜我的父親
at the shrine of my father's skull.
以我的名義所發動的戰爭
A war in my name!
每個人都在喊我的名字
Everyone's shouting my name!
保羅
Paul.
保羅厄崔迪
Paul Atreides.
你是你父親的兒子 你是我的兒子
You are your father's son. You are my son.
你現在是保羅厄崔迪公爵
You are the Duke Paul Atreides.
你知道自己是誰 你知道你是誰
You know who you are. You know who you are.
離我遠點
Get off me!
這一切都怪你
You did this to me!
是你們姐妹會把我變成了怪物
You Bene Gesserit made me a freak!
我父親死了
My father is dead.
有人來了
Someone's near.
你需要水
You need to drink.
這是帳篷過濾后的水
It's recycled water from the tent.
全是汗水和淚
Sweat and tears.
好了 我們走吧
All right, let's get out of here.
是鄧肯
That's Duncan.
鄧肯
Duncan.
夫人 保羅
My lady. Paul.
我很遺憾 你父親
I'm so sorry. Your father...
我們知道了
We know.
公爵大人
My lord Duke.
給
Here.
喝了這個
Drink this.
哈克南人同時襲擊了
Harkonnens hit
這里所有人口密集的區域
every population center on the planet at once.
少說得要10個軍團和上百艘飛船
There must have been 10 legions, hundreds of ships.
薩多卡軍團也參與了 至少有兩個營
There were Sardaukar with them. -At least two battalions.
你確定嗎
-What? Are you sure?
只要你和他們交過手
You cross swords with a Sardaukar,
你就會知道
you know it.
所以 皇帝做出了選擇
So, the Emperor's taken a side.
裁決官你又怎么說
What says the Judge of the Change?
皇帝禁止我透露任何消息
The Emperor forbids me from saying anything at all.
可你還是冒著危險來幫我們
And yet you risk your life to help us.
動作快 遮好飛船
颶沙暴要來了
Storm's coming.
沙暴幾小時后就會到達 這里很安全
The storm will be here in a few hours. We'll be safe here.
知道這是什么地方嗎
Do you know what this place is?
一個早期建造的生態試驗站
It's an old ecological testing station.
他們本想改造這顆星球
They were meant to tame the planet.
把沙子下面的水釋放出來
Free the water locked beneath the sands.
厄拉科斯本可以是個天堂
Arrakis could have been a paradise.
然而工程剛開始 他們就發現了香料
The work had begun, but then the spice was discovered.
于是沒人再提移除沙漠的事
And suddenly no one wanted the desert to go away.
坦納 找幾件適合客人穿的蒸餾服
Tanat, will you find stillsuits to fit our visitors?
是 列特
Yes, Liet.
沙米爾 來幾杯咖啡好嗎
Shamir, a coffee service, please.
馬上來 列特
Of course, Liet.
你和弗雷曼人什么關系
Who are you to the Fremen?
知道各大家族最怕什么嗎 凱恩斯博士
You know what the Great Houses fear most, Dr. Kynes?
正是發生在這兒的一切
Exactly what has happened to us here.
被皇帝的薩多卡軍團各個擊破
The Sardaukar coming and picking them off one by one.
只有團結他們才有可能對抗帝國
Only together can they stand a chance against the Imperium.
你愿意當證人嗎
Would you bear witness?
證明皇帝在這里對我們做的一切
Testify that the Emperor has moved against us here?
如果他們相信我
If they believe me,
各大家族和皇帝之間就會爆發全面戰爭
there would be general warfare between the Great Houses and the Emperor.
戰亂
Chaos
席卷整個帝國
across the Imperium.
要是我能給皇帝第二個選擇呢
Suppose I presented the Emperor with an alternative to chaos.
皇帝沒有兒子 他的女兒尚未出嫁
The Emperor has no sons. And his daughters have yet to marry.
你是想要篡奪皇位嗎
You'd make a play for the throne?
皇帝懼怕厄崔迪家族
The Emperor feared the Atreides.
讓你們來就是為了除掉你們
He brought you here to kill you.
你怎么還不明白
What don't you understand?
你不過是個躲在地下不知所措的孩子
You're a lost boy hiding in a hole in the ground.
弗雷曼人提過李桑阿爾蓋布
The Fremen speak of the  Lisan al-Gaib.
別亂說話
Careful.
意思是“天外之音” 能把他們帶向天堂
The Voice from the Outer World who will lead them to paradise.
迷信而已
Superstition.
我知道你曾愛過一名弗雷曼戰士
I know you loved a Fremen warrior
可他最后戰死沙場
and lost him in battle.
你有著多重身份 在兩股勢力之間周旋
I know you walk in two worlds and are known by many names.
我見過你的夢境
I've seen your dream.
博士 如果我是皇帝
As emperor, Dr. Kynes,
我只要揮揮手就能把厄拉科斯變成天堂
I could make a paradise of Arrakis with a wave of my hand.
你真覺得他是天選之人嗎
他看起來太年輕了
薩多卡軍團
Sardaukar!
不要 鄧肯
No! Duncan!
保羅 不要
Paul, no!
-鄧肯 -不要
- Duncan, no! - No!
-不 -保羅 回來
- No! - Paul, no!
鄧肯 不要
Duncan, no!
-他把門鎖上了 -不
- He's locked the door. - Duncan! No!
他死了
He's gone.
鄧肯
Duncan!
我們得走了 我們別無選擇
We have to go. We have no choice.
保羅 快跑 保羅
Paul, go! Paul!
快跑 跟上
Come on. Come on, come on!
跟著光走
Follow the light.
你們會看到一架撲翼機
You'll find a thopter ready to fly.
外面的颶沙暴是你們最好的掩護
That storm out there is your best shot.
到了5000米以上基本就全是塵土
Above 5,000 meters, it's mostly dust.
飛上去 保持高度
Climb into it. Stay on top.
一直往南 去找弗雷曼人
Head south. Find the Fremen.
你不跟我們一起嗎
Are you not coming with us?
飛行器只有兩個位子
It only seats two.
我會去下一個試驗站
I'll go to the next station
然后向蘭茲拉德聯合會報告
and report this attack to the Landsraad.
怎么去
How?
我是弗雷曼人
I'm Fremen.
沙漠是我的家
The desert's my home.
-一切順利 -你也是
Good luck. Good luck.
凱恩斯 你背叛了皇帝
我只效忠于一個主人
I serve only one master.
他就是
His name is
沙漠之主
Shai-Hulud.
后面有飛機跟著
There are jet flares behind us.
保羅 高度還不夠
Paul. We're not high enough!
絕不能恐懼
I must not fear.
恐懼是思維的殺手
Fear is the mind-killer.
恐懼是最終導致滅亡的死神
Fear is the little death that brings obliteration.
去見朋友
See the friend.
人生的奧秘并不是去解決某個問題
The mystery of life isn't a problem to solve...
而是去經歷眼前的現實
but a reality to experience.
如果你停滯不前便永遠無法參透它
A process that cannot be understood by stopping it.
跟著它的起伏 隨波逐流
We must move with the flow of the process.
勇敢地踏入其中
We must join it.
隨之而動
We must flow with it.
放手
Let go.
他的傷勢還沒有痊愈
我們的人追著他們飛進了颶沙暴
We chased them into a Coriolis storm.
風速達到800公里每小時
Winds at 800 kilometers an hour.
這種情況不可能幸存
Nothing survives such a storm.
他們死定了
They're dead.
毋庸置疑
It's a certainty.
總算了結了
So, it's done. Finally.
給桀迪主星那邊傳話
Send word to Giedi Prime
開始銷售我們儲備的香料
to begin selling our spice reserves.
但是要慢
But slowly.
我不想看到價格下跌
We don't want the price to fall.
你不知道我費了多少勁
You have no idea how much it cost me
才拉攏了薩多卡軍團
to bring such a force to bear here.
我現在只有一個要求
Now I only have one requirement.
回報
Income.
去榨干他們 拉班
So, squeeze, Rabban.
有多少賺多少
Squeeze hard.
是 叔叔
Yes, Uncle.
那弗雷曼人怎么辦
And the Fremen?
統統殺掉
Kill them all.
魁薩茨哈德拉克 站起來 覺醒吧
已經升到5000米以上了
We're above 5,000 meters.
一著陸就往巖石上跑
As soon as we land, run for the rocks.
用這個來呼吸
And breathe through this.
現在要去找弗雷曼人
Now we have to find the Fremen.
你還好嗎
Are you good?
沒事
Yeah.
跟著那個朋友
不要感到害怕
Don't be frightened.
就連小小的沙鼠都能活下來
Even a little desert mouse can survive.
不要感到害怕 你必須面對你的恐懼
Don't be frightened. You'll need to face your fears.
一位朋友…
A friend...
一位朋友會幫助你
A friend will help you.
跟著那位朋友
Follow the friend.
你要學的還有很多
You have much to learn.
我來教你如何在沙漠里生存
And I will show you the ways of the desert.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
地下城 鄧肯在那兒住過
The sietch where Duncan lived
應該就在前邊
is somewhere off that way.
我看到了綠色植被
I can see greenery over there.
在那兒
There.
說明弗雷曼人就住那兒
That means Fremen live there.
等天黑了再穿過去
We'll cross after dark.
弗雷曼人就是這么干的
That's how the Fremen do it.
就快進入沙蟲的領地了
We're about to enter worm territory.
我們不能像普通人那么走路
We can't walk like regular humans.
那樣做 我們就死定了
If we do, we're dead.
得像弗雷曼人那樣 走沙地微步
We'll have to walk like the Fremen do. It's called a sandwalk.
至少家里的百科全書上是這么說的
At least according to the filmbooks back home.
好的 明白了
Yeah. Yeah, okay.
好的 跟著我
Okay. Follow me.
像我這樣走
Do the same moves.
方向應該沒錯
I think this is the right direction.
它就在附近 我們快走
It's close by. Let's get out of here.
等等
Wait.
是鼓沙
It's drum sand.
快跑
run.
Go! Go!
是沙槌
It's a thumper.
有人啟動了沙槌
Someone set off a thumper.
保羅 快跑
Paul! Run!
它們究竟有多大 剛才太恐怖了
How big are they? That was insane.
有人引開了它
Someone called it.
這里還有別人
不要跑
Do not run.
那樣只會耗費你們身上的水分
You will only waste your body's water.
慢著
Hold.
斯第爾格
Stilgar.
嘿 你認識我
Hey! You know me.
你來找我父親時我也在場
I was there when you came to my father's Council.
這位是公爵的兒子
This is the Duke's son.
你還在等什么  我們需要他們的水分
Why are you waiting? We need their water.
這就是我和你們提過的男孩兒
This is the boy I told you about.
我們不能動他
We can't touch him.
他怎么會是李桑阿爾蓋布
他還沒有證明自己
他們是弱者
They are weaklings.
詹米
Jamis.
他們倆從沙漠之主的眼皮底下來到這里
That was a brave crossing they made in the path of  Shai-Hulud.
我并不覺得他是一個懦弱的人
He does not speak or act like a weakling.
他父親也一樣
Nor did his father.
是我的沙槌救了他
My thumper saved his life.
理智一點 斯第爾格
Go back to reason, Stilgar.
他不是天選之人
He's not The One.
我們有許多有權勢的朋友
We have powerful friends.
你們幫我們離開這里 去卡拉丹
You help us off-world, to Caladan,
到時候一定重重有賞
you will be well rewarded.
有什么比你們身體里的水分更值錢
What wealth can you offer beyond the water in your flesh?
那小子還小 可以慢慢培養
The boy is young. He can learn our ways.
他可以留下來
He may have sanctuary.
但那個女的 沒受過訓練
But the woman is untrained...
歲數太大 沒法訓練
and too old to learn.
退后 你們這群蠢貨
back, you dogs.
她會割了我的喉嚨
She'll cut my throat.
為什么不說清楚你受過訓練  是個女戰士
Why didn't you say you were a weirding woman? And a fighter?
你們給我機會說了嗎
Conversation ran short.
冷靜點 女人
Peace, woman.
冷靜點
Peace.
我剛才太武斷了
I judged hastily.
太陽就快升起
我們必須回地下城去
等回去后再決定這兩個人的命運
在那之前
他們會得到我的庇護
這是我的承諾
我不會讓你傷害我的朋友
I would not have let you hurt my friends.
他們說你是救世主
They say you're the  Mahdi.
我看你只是個孩子罷了
But you look like a little boy.
你選了條最難的路爬上來
You chose the hardest way up.
跟著我
Follow me.
我們得走了
把它給我
Give it to me.
等你有資格時 自然會得到毛拉槍
You will have your own maula pistol when you've earned it.
把它給我
Give it to me.
契妮 照顧好這兩個新來的
Chani, take charge of the newcomers.
確保他們一路安全 走吧
See that they are safe on the journey. Let's go.
我不接受他們
I will not have them.
詹米
Jamis,
我已經說過了 別亂來
I have spoken. Be still.
你說得自己像個領袖一樣
You talk like a leader.
但最強的才有資格領導
But the strongest leads.
她打敗了你
She bested you.
我現在要求決斗
I invoke the amtal.
你不能挑戰薩亞迪娜女祭司
You may not challenge a Sayyadina.
那就找個人代她出戰
Then who will fight in her name?
詹米 別鬧了
Jamis, don't do this.
夠了 黑夜就要過去了
Don't. The night is fading.
那就讓太陽見證這場決斗
Then the sun will witness this death.
她的勇士在哪兒
Where is her champion?
我接受這個人選
I accept her champion.
保羅厄崔迪必須死去
Paul Atreides must die...
為了魁薩茨哈德拉克的崛起
for  Kwisatz Haderach  to rise.
不要感到害怕
Don't be frightened.
也不要抗拒
Don't resist.
如果終將奪人性命 那就選擇你自己
When you take a life, you take your own.
我雖然不信你是天外之音
I don't believe you're the  Lisan al-Gaib.
但我仍然希望你死得有尊嚴
But I want you to die with honor.
這把晶牙匕是我姑婆給我的
This crysknife was given to me by my great aunt.
是由沙漠之主的牙齒制成的
It's made from a tooth of  Shai-Hulud.
神圣的沙蟲
The great sandworm.
拿著它 死了也是有尊嚴的
This will be a great honor, for you to die holding it.
異星人在哪里
Where is the Outworlder?
詹米是個出色的戰士
Jamis is a good fighter.
你不會太痛苦
He won't let you suffer.
契妮
Chani...
沒什么
Um...
Never mind.
愿你刀毀人亡
May thy knife chip and shatter.
你應該感謝我的刀
You should welcome my blade.
這個世界會要了你的小命
This world will kill you.
這樣一來反倒干脆
Quicker this way.
認不認輸
Do you yield?
這孩子不懂我們的規矩
The boy doesn't know our rule.
決斗中沒有認輸的余地
There's no yielding under the amtal rule.
不是你死就是我亡
Only death is the test of it.
他是在戲弄他嗎
-Is he toying with him?
不
-No.
保羅從沒殺過人
Paul has never killed a man.
魁薩茨哈德拉克
Kwisatz Haderach.
魁薩茨哈德拉克 站起來 覺醒吧
Kwisatz Haderach. Climb up. Rise.
你是我們的一員了
You're one of us now.
一命換一命
A life for a life.
跟我們走 去地下城
Come with us to  Sietch  Tabr.
不
No.
保羅必須離開這里
Paul needs to get off-world.
你一定有辦法 你們中有走私徒
You must have ways. You have smugglers,
-你們有飛船 你們還有… -不
you have ships. - No. - You have...
皇帝派我們來這里 我父親來了
The Emperor sent us to this place. And my father came,
不是為了香料 也不是為了財富
not for spice, not for the riches,
為的是弗雷曼人的力量
but for the strength of your people.
命運指引我走向沙漠
My road leads into the desert.
我能看見
I can see it.
只要你們愿意接受我們
If you'll have us,
我們就跟你們走
we will come.
沙漠的力量
Desert power.
一切才剛開始
This is only the beginning.
（改編自弗蘭克赫伯特著作《沙丘》）
沙丘